CHRISTOPHER MICHAEL ROZARIO

Website: https://www.christopherrozario.xyz

Phone: +91 9479710111, Email: christopherrozario7@gmail.com
Full Stack Developer, B.E Computer Science Engineering

SUMMARY

Dedicated Software developer with **can do attitude**, have problem solving and critical thinking abilities. Have experience in both front and back end technologies. Have experience in **Java and Javascript frameworks**. Also have public cloud platform experience with a **certification in AWS**. Part of Cognizant Blockchain practice and have experience in distributed blockchain solutions, was also part of commercial IOT solutions team and have experience on IOT projects. Developer with experience of implementing solutions in agile environment.

I have strong commitment, dedication and efficient problem solving capabilities I am a quick learner, adaptable and flexible to the ever-changing technology.

EDUCATION QUALIFICATION

Year	Degree/Certificate	University/Board	Percentage
2014-2018	B.E. (C.S.E.)	R.G.P.V	8.64 CGPA
2014	Class XII	CBSE	92.60%
2012	Class X	CBSE	95.00%

TECHNICAL SKILLS

• Languages Java, Javascript, SQL, HTML, C++, Web Services, JSON

Framework & Technologies Spring boot, Angular, Web Services (RESTful), JPA, Log4J

Databases MySQL, PostgreSQL

Development Tools
 Deployment Tools
 Ansible, Jenkins, docker, docker compose

• Platforms Linux, Windows

Cloud Infrastructure AWS

Others
 MS Word, MS PowerPoint, MS Excel

EXPERIENCE

• Cognizant Technological Solutions, Pune & Chennai

Aug, 2018 - Present

Associate Projects - CDE Blockchain community

- Developed Blockchain and IOT solutions. Had experience in designing and implementation of multitier applications using web-based technologies like **Spring Boot**.
- Good experience in developing applications with RESTful Web Services.
- Responsible for developing an Admin module, a one point portal to manage and monitor all the
 moving parts and users of our solution. Had experience in ELK stack to collect logs from various
 microservices so that useful information can be derived from it to take business decisions.
- Experience in developing deployment strategies to build docker images of applications and helped in decreasing man hours and error vulnerability by deployment automation scripts made using Ansible and Jenkins.

- Experienced in developing solutions for production and had major learning in its security standards and good practices.
- Developed a supply chain POC on hyperledger. Responsible for developing backend for the project using spring boot. Also part of development of UI using **Angular**.
- Part of Cognizant internal IOT project for facility management. Worked on backend part using express.js and **Dynamo DB**. Had experience in cloud infrastructure for an IOT project. Also had experience of multiple offerings in **AWS**.

• Juspay Technologies, Bangalore

Feb, 2018 - June, 2018

SDE Intern

- Experienced software development and working environment in a start up.
- Experienced functional programming and part of developing OAuth 2.0 authorization using Prescript.

• Vedisoft Software Solutions, Bhopal

July, 2017 - Nov, 2017

Project Intern

• Part of team building a management software in J2EE architecture for a Builder group in Bhopal to manage their transactions and members. Had experience Java, J2EE, JSP, JQuery

CERTIFICATIONS

AWS Certified Developer – Associate

Certificate No. 4J3K8TBD2EE1QPST Score: 927 / 1000

Oracle Certified Associate, Java 7 Programmer

Certificate No. 248412639OCAJSE7 Aggregate: 90.00 / 100.00

Certified Blockchain Expert

Certificate No. 13641485 Aggregate: 91.00 / 100.00

ACHIEVEMENTS

- Won internal community Hackathon and also won a Bronze award for performance in Cognizant.
- Amongst Top 8 teams in SMART INDIA HACKATHON 2017 grand finale for ministry of AYUSH, govt. of INDIA
- Won inter college coding competitions like CODE ENIGMA 2015, GAME OF CODES 2015.

WEB LINKS

- GitHub https://github.com/christo707
- LinkedIn https://www.linkedin.com/in/christopher-michael-rozario-7352b8107/
- Facebook https://www.facebook.com/christopher.m.rozario

PERSONAL DETAILS

- **Date of Birth** 25- Jul-1996
- Known Languages Hindi, English
- Email: christopherrozario7@gmail.com
- **Phone Numbers:** +91-9479710111, +91-9131449948